<resources>
    <string name="app_name">SugarSense</string>
    <string name="title_home">Home</string>
    <string name="title_graph_analysis">Graph Analysis</string>
    <string name="title_remedies">Remedies</string>
    <string name="title_explore_more">Explore More</string>
    <string name="welcome"><u>WELCOME</u></string>
    <string name="do_not_have_an_account">Do not Have An Account??</string>
    <string name="login">LOGIN</string>
    <string name="todo">TODO</string>
    <string name="todo1">TODO</string>
    <string name="todo2">TODO</string>
    <string name="forgot_password">Forgot Password</string>
    <string name="email">EMAIL</string>
    <string name="password">PASSWORD</string>
    <string name="new_user"><u>NEW USER</u></string>
    <string name="sign_up">SIGN UP</string>
    <string name="forgot">FORGOT</string>
    <string name="submit">SUBMIT</string>
    <string name="retrieve_account"><u>RETRIEVE ACCOUNT</u></string>
    <string name="create_account">CREATE ACCOUNT</string>
    <string name="note_your_password_must_contain_6_letters">NOTE : YOUR PASSWORD MUST CONTAIN 6 LETTERS</string>
    <string name="confirm_logout"><u>𝐂𝐎𝐍𝐅𝐈𝐑𝐌 𝐋𝐎𝐆𝐎𝐔𝐓</u></string>
    <string name="do_you_really_want_to_logout">DO YOU REALLY WANT TO LOGOUT??</string>
    <string name="cancel">CANCEL</string>
    <string name="logout">LOGOUT</string>
    <string name="Fasting_and_PP_test">Enter Your Glucose Fasting (F) and Post Meal (PP) Test Results</string>
    <string name="enter_your_fasting_sugar_test_restult_here"><u>Enter Your Fasting Sugar Test Restults Here...</u></string>
    <string name="enter_your_pp_sugar_test_restult_here"><u>Enter Your PP Sugar Test Restults Here...</u></string>
    <string name="test_1">Test 1 :</string>
    <string name="test_2">Test 2 :</string>
    <string name="test_3">Test 3 :</string>
    <string name="test_4">Test 4 :</string>
    <string name="test_5">Test 5 :</string>
    <string name="test_6">Test 6 :</string>
    <string name="test_7">Test 7 :</string>
    <string name="delete_user_data">Delete User Data</string>
    <string name="do_you_really_want_to_delete_user_data">DO YOU REALLY WANT TO DELETE USER DATA??</string>
    <string name="note">Note : You wont be able to retrieve back your data if you press \'DELETE\'</string>
    <string name="delete">DELETE</string>
    <string name="blood_sugar_level_analysis">BLOOD SUGAR LEVEL ANALYSIS</string>
    <string name="welcome_back">WELCOME BACK,</string>
    <string name="diabetes_risk_analysis"><i>Diabetes Risk Analysis</i></string>
    <string name="your_analysis_report"><i>Your Analysis Report</i></string>
    <string name="see_more"><u><i>see more</i></u></string>
    <string name="see_less"><u><i>see less</i></u></string>
    <string name="health_risks_of_diebetes"><u>Health Risks Of Diabetes</u></string>
    <string name="health_risks_description"><br>Diabetes is a chronic condition that affects how your body metabolizes glucose, the main source of energy for cells. There are two main types of diabetes: type 1 and type 2. Both types can lead to various health risks if not properly managed:\n\n\n</br><br><b>1.Cardiovascular Disease:</b> Diabetes significantly increases the risk of various cardiovascular problems, including coronary artery disease, heart attack, stroke, and narrowing of arteries (atherosclerosis).\n\n</br><br><b>2.Nerve Damage (Neuropathy):</b> High blood sugar levels can damage the small blood vessels that nourish nerves, especially in the legs. This can lead to tingling, numbness, burning, or pain that usually begins at the tips of the toes or fingers and gradually spreads upward.\n\n</br><br><b>3.Kidney Damage (Nephropathy):</b> Diabetes can damage the kidneys\' filtering system, leading to kidney disease or even kidney failure over time.\n\n</br><br><b>4.Eye Damage (Retinopathy):</b> Diabetes can damage the blood vessels of the retina, leading to diabetic retinopathy, which can cause vision problems and blindness if left untreated.\n\n</br><br><b>5.Foot Damage:</b> Nerve damage and poor blood flow can lead to foot problems. In severe cases, this can result in serious infections, which may ultimately require amputation of toes, feet, or legs.\n\n</br><br><b>6.Skin Conditions:</b> Diabetes may leave you more susceptible to skin problems, including bacterial and fungal infections.\n\n</br><br><b>7.Hearing Impairment:</b> Hearing loss is more common in people with diabetes.\n\n</br><br><b>8.Alzheimer\'s Disease:</b> There is growing evidence that diabetes may be linked to an increased risk of Alzheimer\'s disease and other forms of dementia.\n\n</br><br><b>9.Depression:</b> People with diabetes have a higher risk of depression and anxiety than those without the condition.\n\n</br><br><b>10.Gastroparesis:</b> This condition affects how the stomach empties, causing nausea, vomiting, and problems with blood sugar levels and nutrition.\n\n\n</br>These complications underscore the importance of managing diabetes through lifestyle modifications, such as maintaining a healthy diet, regular exercise, monitoring blood sugar levels, taking prescribed medications, and regular check-ups with healthcare providers. Early detection and proper management can help reduce the risk of complications and improve overall quality of life for individuals living with diabetes.</string>
    <string name="diet_type"><i><u>DIET TYPE</u></i></string>
    <string name="vegetarian_diet_text"><br>A vegetarian diet can be an excellent choice for individuals with diabetes, as it often includes plenty of nutrient-rich foods and can be high in fiber, which helps control blood sugar levels. Here\'s a sample vegetarian diet plan for diabetes:\n\n</br><br>Breakfast:\n\n</br><br>Option 1:\n</br><br>1 cup of cooked oatmeal topped with sliced strawberries and a handful of chopped almonds.\n1 cup of unsweetened almond milk or low-fat yogurt.\n</br><br>Option 2:\n</br><br>2 whole-grain toast slices topped with avocado slices and cherry tomatoes.\n\n</br><br>Beverage:\n</br><br>Unsweetened herbal tea or black coffee.\n\n</br><br>Mid-Morning Snack:\n</br>A small apple or a pear.\nA handful of raw almonds or walnuts.\n\nLunch:\n\nOption 1:\nMixed vegetable salad with leafy greens, cucumbers, bell peppers, and cherry tomatoes.\nQuinoa or brown rice with stir-fried tofu and mixed vegetables.\nOption 2:\nLentil soup with assorted vegetables. Whole-grain chapati (Indian flatbread) with a side of spinach or other leafy greens.\nOption 3:\nChickpea curry with spinach served with brown rice or whole-grain roti.\nA side of cucumber raita (yogurt dip) with diced cucumbers, tomatoes, and mint.\n\nAfternoon Snack:\n\nCarrot sticks with hummus.\nGreek yogurt with a sprinkle of cinnamon.\n\nDinner:\n\nOption 1:\nGrilled vegetable skewers (zucchini, bell peppers, onions) served with quinoa.\nBaked tofu or tempeh marinated in a low-sodium soy sauce.\nOption 2:\nStuffed bell peppers with a filling of quinoa, black beans, corn, and diced tomatoes.\nMixed green salad with olive oil and vinegar dressing.\nOption 3:\nSpaghetti squash pasta with marinara sauce and sautéed mushrooms and spinach.\nA side of steamed broccoli or green beans.\n\nEvening Snack:\n\nAir-popped popcorn sprinkled with nutritional yeast or a small handful of mixed nuts.\n\nBefore Bed:\n\nA small cup of low-fat milk or unsweetened almond milk.\n\nAdditional Tips:\nDrink plenty of water throughout the day to stay hydrated.\nBe mindful of portion sizes and aim for balanced meals.\nLimit intake of processed foods, sugary snacks, and high-fat dairy products.\nMonitor blood sugar levels regularly and adjust your diet as needed in consultation with your healthcare provider.</string>
    <string name="non_vegetarian_diet_text"><br>A non vegetarian diet can be an excellent choice for individuals with diabetes, as it often includes plenty of nutrient-rich foods and can be high in fiber, which helps control blood sugar levels. Here\'s a sample non vegetarian diet plan for diabetes:\n\nBreakfast:\n\nOption 1:\n2 scrambled eggs cooked with spinach and tomatoes.\n1 slice of whole-grain toast.\nOption 2:\nGreek yogurt parfait with mixed berries and a sprinkle of almonds.\nHard-boiled egg.\n\nMid-Morning Snack:\n\nSliced cucumber and bell pepper sticks with hummus.\n\nLunch:\n\nOption 1:\nGrilled chicken breast with a side of quinoa and roasted vegetables (bell peppers, zucchini, and broccoli).\nOption 2:\nBaked salmon fillet with a mixed green salad (spinach, arugula, cherry tomatoes) and a light vinaigrette dressing.\nOption 3:\nTurkey and avocado wrap with whole-grain tortilla, lettuce, and sliced tomatoes.\n\nAfternoon Snack:\n\nCottage cheese with sliced strawberries or a small apple.\n\nDinner:\n\nOption 1:\nLean beef stir-fry with mixed vegetables (broccoli, carrots, bell peppers) served with brown rice.\nOption 2:\nGrilled shrimp skewers with quinoa and steamed asparagus.\nOption 3:\nBaked chicken thighs with roasted sweet potatoes and green beans.\n\nEvening Snack:\n\nA small handful of almonds or walnuts.\n\nBefore Bed:\n\nA small cup of low-fat milk or unsweetened almond milk.\n\nAdditional Tips:\n\nChoose lean protein sources such as skinless poultry, fish, seafood, and lean cuts of beef or pork.\nIncorporate plenty of non-starchy vegetables into your meals for added fiber and nutrients.\nOpt for whole grains like brown rice, quinoa, whole-grain bread, and whole-wheat pasta to help manage blood sugar levels.\nBe mindful of portion sizes and avoid high-calorie, high-fat sauces and dressings.\nLimit processed meats, fried foods, and sugary snacks.\nMonitor blood sugar levels regularly and adjust your diet as needed in consultation with your healthcare provider.</br></string>
    <string name="flexitarian_diet_text"><br>A flexitarian diet emphasizes plant-based foods while still allowing for occasional consumption of animal products. This approach can be beneficial for individuals with diabetes as it focuses on nutrient-rich foods and can help manage blood sugar levels. Here\'s a sample flexitarian diet plan for diabetes:\n\nBreakfast:\n\nOption 1:\nOvernight oats made with rolled oats, unsweetened almond milk, chia seeds, and topped with sliced strawberries and a sprinkle of nuts.\nOption 2:\nScrambled tofu with spinach, tomatoes, and bell peppers served with whole-grain toast.\nOption 3:\nGreek yogurt parfait with mixed berries, a drizzle of honey, and a handful of granola.\n\nMid-Morning Snack:\n\nCarrot and celery sticks with hummus.\n\nLunch:\n\nOption 1:\nLentil soup with mixed vegetables and a side of whole-grain bread.\nOption 2:\nQuinoa salad with black beans, corn, cherry tomatoes, avocado, and a light vinaigrette dressing.\nOption 3:\nChickpea and vegetable stir-fry served with brown rice.\n\nAfternoon Snack:\n\nCottage cheese with sliced cucumber and cherry tomatoes.\n\nDinner:\n\nOption 1:\nBaked salmon fillet with roasted sweet potatoes and steamed broccoli.\nOption 2:\nTofu and vegetable curry served with quinoa or brown rice.\nOption 3:\nGrilled chicken breast with a mixed green salad and a side of roasted vegetables.\n\nEvening Snack:\n\nA small handful of mixed nuts or a piece of fruit.\n\nBefore Bed:\n\nA cup of herbal tea or a small glass of low-fat milk.\n\nAdditional Tips:\nEmphasize plant-based foods such as fruits, vegetables, legumes, nuts, seeds, and whole grains in your meals.\nInclude a variety of protein sources, including beans, lentils, tofu, tempeh, fish, poultry, and dairy products.\nLimit red meat and processed meats, opting for lean protein sources more often.\nChoose whole grains over refined grains to help manage blood sugar levels. Be mindful of portion sizes and avoid excessive consumption of high-calorie foods.\nMonitor blood sugar levels regularly and adjust your diet as needed in consultation with your healthcare provider.</br></string>
    <string name="homeopathic_remedy_description"><br>Homeopathy is a holistic system of medicine that treats each individual based on their unique symptoms, rather than just the disease itself. While some homeopathic remedies are suggested for diabetes management, it\'s important to note that homeopathy should not replace conventional medical treatment for diabetes. Instead, it can be used as a complementary approach alongside conventional treatments. Here are some common homeopathic remedies that are sometimes used for diabetes:\n\n<b><u>Syzygium Jambolanum:</u></b> This remedy is often recommended for diabetes with symptoms like excessive thirst, frequent urination, and weakness.\n<b><u>Phosphoric Acid:</u></b> It may be suggested for diabetes with symptoms like extreme weakness, debility, and mental depression.\n<b><u>Uranium Nitricum:</u></b> This remedy may be used for diabetes with symptoms such as excessive thirst, frequent urination at night, and weakness.\n<b><u>Phosphorus:</u></b> It might be recommended for diabetes with symptoms such as weakness, exhaustion, and a tendency to faint.\n><b><u>Lycopodium:</u></b> This remedy may be suggested for diabetes with symptoms like flatulence, bloating, and cravings for sweets.\n<b><u>Arsenicum Album:</u></b> It might be used for diabetes with symptoms like burning pains, restlessness, and anxiety.\n<b><u>Natrum Sulphuricum:</u></b> This remedy is sometimes recommended for diabetes with symptoms like a sluggish liver, excessive thirst, and urination at night.\n<b><u>Acidum Phosphoricum:</u></b> It may be suggested for diabetes with symptoms such as weakness, fatigue, and loss of libido. \n\nIt\'s important to consult with a qualified homeopathic practitioner who can take your complete case history and prescribe the most appropriate remedy based on your individual symptoms and constitution. Additionally, remember to continue monitoring blood sugar levels and follow any prescribed conventional treatments for diabetes under the guidance of your healthcare provider. Homeopathy should always be used as a complementary approach and not as a substitute for conventional medical care.</br></string>
    <string name="ayurvedic_remedy_description"><br>Ayurveda, the traditional system of medicine from India, offers several herbal remedies and lifestyle practices that are believed to help manage diabetes. Here are some Ayurvedic remedies commonly recommended for diabetes management:\n\n<b><u>Bitter Gourd (Karela):</u></b> Bitter gourd is often used in Ayurveda for its anti-diabetic properties. Drinking bitter gourd juice on an empty stomach in the morning is believed to help lower blood sugar levels. \n<b><u>Indian Gooseberry (Amla):</u></b> Amla is rich in vitamin C and antioxidants, which are beneficial for overall health. Consuming amla juice or incorporating amla powder into your diet may help regulate blood sugar levels.\n<b><u>Fenugreek (Methi):</u></b> Fenugreek seeds are high in soluble fiber, which can help lower blood sugar levels by slowing down the absorption of carbohydrates. Soaking fenugreek seeds overnight and consuming them in the morning is a common Ayurvedic remedy for diabetes.\n<u><b>Cinnamon (Dalchini):</b></u> Cinnamon is believed to improve insulin sensitivity and lower blood sugar levels. Adding cinnamon powder to your meals or beverages may help in managing diabetes. \n<b><u>Turmeric (Haldi):</u></b> Curcumin, the active compound in turmeric, has anti-inflammatory and antioxidant properties that may benefit people with diabetes. Consuming turmeric powder mixed with warm milk or water is a popular Ayurvedic remedy.\n<b><u>Gymnema Sylvestre (Gurmar):</u></b> Gurmar, also known as the sugar destroyer,is an herb used in Ayurvedic medicine to help control blood sugar levels. It is believed to reduce sugar cravings and improve insulin production.\n<b><u>Neem:</u></b> Neem leaves are considered beneficial for diabetic patients due to their anti-diabetic properties. Drinking neem leaf extract or chewing neem leaves is believed to help regulate blood sugar levels.\n<b><u>Holy Basil (Tulsi):</u></b> Holy basil is known for its adaptogenic properties, which may help the body cope with stress and regulate blood sugar levels. Drinking tulsi tea or consuming fresh tulsi leaves may be beneficial for diabetes management.\n<b><u>Triphala:</u></b> Triphala is a combination of three fruits: Amla, Haritaki, and Bibhitaki. It is commonly used in Ayurveda to promote digestion and detoxification. Some studies suggest that Triphala may help improve insulin sensitivity and lower blood sugar levels.\n<b><u>Lifestyle Practices:</u></b> Ayurveda emphasizes the importance of maintaining a healthy lifestyle to manage diabetes. This includes following a balanced diet, engaging in regular exercise, practicing stress management techniques such as yoga and meditation, and getting an adequate amount of sleep. \n\nIt\'s important to consult with a qualified Ayurvedic practitioner or healthcare provider before using any herbal remedies for diabetes, especially if you are already taking medications for diabetes or other health conditions. They can provide guidance on the appropriate dosage and potential interactions with other treatments. Additionally, herbal remedies should complement, not replace, conventional medical treatment for diabetes.</br></string>
    <string name="allopethic_remedies_description"><br>Allopathic remedies for diabetes typically involve medications aimed at controlling blood sugar levels and reducing the risk of complications. Here are some common allopathic treatments for diabetes:\n\n<b><u>Oral Medications:\nMetformin:\n</u></b> This is usually the first-line medication for type 2 diabetes. It works by decreasing glucose production in the liver and improving insulin sensitivity.\n<b><u>Sulfonylureas:</u></b> Drugs like glipizide, glyburide, and glimepiride stimulate the pancreas to release more insulin.\n<b><u>DPP-4 Inhibitors:</u></b> These medications (e.g., sitagliptin, saxagliptin) help lower blood sugar levels by preventing the breakdown of incretin hormones, which stimulate insulin release.\n<b><u>SGLT2 Inhibitors:</u></b> Drugs like empagliflozin, dapagliflozin, and canagliflozin lower blood sugar by causing the kidneys to remove sugar through urine.\n\n<b><u>Injectable Medications:</u></b>\n<b><u>Insulin:</u></b> Various types of insulin are available, including rapid-acting, short-acting, intermediate-acting, and long-acting. Insulin therapy may be necessary for people with type 1 diabetes and for some people with type 2 diabetes who cannot adequately control their blood sugar levels with oral medications alone.\n<b><u>Combination Medications:</u></b> Some medications combine different classes of drugs to provide multiple mechanisms of action and improve blood sugar control.\n<b><u>Monitoring Devices:</u></b> Allopathic treatments often involve the use of blood glucose monitors, continuous glucose monitors (CGMs), and insulin pumps to help individuals monitor their blood sugar levels and manage insulin therapy more effectively.\n<b><u>Lifestyle Modifications:</u></b> While not strictly allopathic, healthcare providers often recommend lifestyle changes such as diet modification, regular exercise, weight management, and smoking cessation alongside medication to help control diabetes.\n<b><u>Regular Monitoring and Medical Care:</u></b> People with diabetes require regular medical check-ups to monitor their blood sugar levels, assess the effectiveness of their treatment plan, and screen for complications.\n\nIt\'s important for individuals with diabetes to work closely with their healthcare providers to determine the most appropriate treatment plan based on their specific needs, medical history, and lifestyle factors. Additionally, adherence to prescribed medications and regular follow-up visits are crucial for effective diabetes management.</br></string>
    <string name="life_style_changes_remediees_description"><br>Lifestyle changes play a crucial role in managing diabetes. Here are some specific lifestyle changes and remedies tailored to help control blood sugar levels:\n\n<b><u>Healthy Eating Habits:</u></b> Focus on a balanced diet rich in fiber, whole grains, lean proteins, and healthy fats.\nChoose low glycemic index (GI) foods that cause slower rises in blood sugar levels, such as whole grains, legumes, and non-starchy vegetables.\nControl portion sizes to avoid overeating, which can lead to spikes in blood sugar levels.\n<b><u>Regular Physical Activity:</u></b> Aim for at least 150 minutes of moderate-intensity aerobic exercise per week, such as brisk walking, cycling, or swimming.\nIncorporate strength training exercises at least two days a week to improve muscle strength and insulin sensitivity.\nStay active throughout the day by taking short walks, using stairs instead of elevators, or doing household chores.\n<b><u>Weight Management:</u></b> Achieve and maintain a healthy weight through a combination of diet and exercise.\nSet realistic weight loss goals and make gradual changes to your eating and activity habits.\nWork with a healthcare provider or registered dietitian to develop a personalized weight loss plan.\n<b><u>Stress Reduction:</u></b> Practice stress-reducing techniques such as meditation, deep breathing exercises, yoga, or tai chi.\nEngage in hobbies and activities that you enjoy to help relieve stress and promote relaxation.\nPrioritize self-care and allocate time for relaxation and leisure activities.\n<b><u>Adequate Sleep:</u></b> Aim for 7-9 hours of quality sleep per night.\nEstablish a regular sleep schedule and create a relaxing bedtime routine.\nAvoid caffeine, electronic devices, and stimulating activities before bedtime.\n<b><u>Quit Smoking:</u></b> If you smoke, seek support to quit smoking as it can worsen diabetes complications and increase the risk of heart disease.\nUse smoking cessation programs, nicotine replacement therapy, or counseling to help you quit.\n<b><u>Limit Alcohol Consumption:</u></b> Drink alcohol in moderation, if at all, as it can cause fluctuations in blood sugar levels.\nLimit alcohol intake to one drink per day for women and up to two drinks per day for men.\n<b><u>Regular Monitoring and Healthcare:</u></b> Monitor blood sugar levels regularly using a blood glucose meter or continuous glucose monitoring system.\nAttend regular check-ups with your healthcare provider to monitor your diabetes management and adjust treatment as needed.\nKeep track of your progress and make adjustments to your lifestyle habits as necessary to maintain optimal blood sugar control.\n\nBy incorporating these lifestyle changes into your daily routine, you can effectively manage diabetes and improve your overall health and well-being. Remember to consult with your healthcare provider before making any significant changes to your diabetes management plan.</br></string>

</resources>